Guide to the Electrical Workers of Western Pennsylvania Oral History Project, 1976-1977 AIS.1991.15
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Electrical Workers of Western Pennsylvania Oral History Project
1976-1977
ULS Archives & Special Collections
AIS.1991.15
0.21 Linear Feet (1 box)
This collection of cassette tapes contains interviews with electrical workers from the General Electric plant in Erie, Pennsylvania, and the Westinghouse plant in East Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. These interviews contain information about working conditions, discrimination, company resistance to unionization, and the red-baiting of union organizers. The cassettes were copied for the Archives Service Center by the Pennsylvania Historical and Museum Commission.
History
This collection of cassette tapes contains interviews with electrical workers from the General Electric plant in Erie, Pa., and the Westinghouse plant in East Pittsburgh, Pa. The interviews were conducted by University of Pittsburgh doctoral candidate Ronald W. Schatz in 1976-1977 and used to complete his 1983 book The Electrical Workers: a History of Labor at General Electric and Westinghouse, 1923-1960. The cassettes were copied for the Archives Service Center by the Pennsylvania Historical and Museum Commission.
Scope and Content Notes
These interviews with retired electrical workers contain information about working conditions, discrimination, company resistance to unionization, and the red-baiting of union organizers at the General Electric plant in Erie, Pennsylvania, and the Westinghouse plant in East Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. Many of the interviews have been transcribed by the Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh, and are present in Box 1 of the collection.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged alphabetically by the subject's last name.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Pennsylvania Historical and Museum Commission in 1991.
Previous Citation
Electrical Workers of Western Pennsylvania Oral History Project, 1976-1977, AIS.1991.15, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Existence and Location of Originals
The tapes within this collection are copies of the originals which belong to the Pennsylvania Historical and Museum Commission of the Pennsylvania State Archives.
Related Archival Material
The Electrical Workers: a History of Labor at General Electric and Westinghouse, 1923-1960 by Ronald W. Schatz is available at the Archives Service Center under call number HD8039.E32 U67 1983.
American electrical workers: work, struggles, aspirations, 1930-1950 by Ronald W. Schatz is available at the Archives Service Center in the University Archives Theses.
Separated Material
Cassette tapes of the interviews can be found in Audio Cassette Cabinet 3/5.
Erie (Pa.); Pittsburgh (Pa.); Labor; Oral histories (Document genres); Electric industry workers; Stasik, Margaret Darin; United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America; Winn, William; Yeager, Otto; Rice, Charles Owen; Balent, Marie Downey; Clarke, Maxine; Copeland, Charles E.; Doutt, Anna; Doutt, Norman; Gides, Emery L.; Heberlin, Joseph; Kacsmarek, Hattie; Lehan, Edward; Meer, Rose; Mikalowski, Philip; Modran, George; O'Connor, Patrick; Peeler, William H.; Pugliano, Frank J.; Quinn, Thomas J.; Rath, Eugene; Samokar, Michael; Smith, Alice; Smith, Dave
- Balent, Marie Downey, March 9, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Clarke, Maxine, August 17, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Copeland, Charles E., May 14, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Heberlin, Joseph, August 8, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Hill, Edith (pseudonym), August 16, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Meer, Rose, March 18, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Mikalowski, Philip (pseudonym), August 17, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- O'Connor, Patrick, May 7, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Peeler, William H., April 20, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Quinn, Thomas J., April 14, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Stasik, Margaret Darin, January 7, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Yeager, Otto, January 6, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Balent, Marie Downey, March 9, 1977 (Box 1, Cassette 1)
- Clarke, Maxine, August 17, 1976 (Box 1, Cassette 2)
- Copeland, Charles E., May 14, 1977 (Box 1, Cassette 3)
- Doutt, Anna, August 16, 1976 (Box 1, Cassette 4)
- Doutt, Norman, August 16, 1976 (Box 1, Cassette 05-06)
- Gides, Emery L., August 19, 1976 (Box 1, Cassette 07-08)
- Hill, Edith (pseudonym), August 16, 1976 (Box 1, Cassette 09-10)
- Heberlin, Joseph, August 8, 1976 (Box 1, Cassette 11)
- Kacsmarek, Hattie, August 19, 1976 (Box 1, Cassette 12)
- Lehan, Edward, August 8, 1976 (Box 1, Cassette 13)
- Meer, Rose, March 18, 1977 (Box 1, Cassette 14)
- Mikalowski, Philip (pseudonym), August 17, 1976 (Box 1, Cassette 15)
- Modran, George, December 15, 1976 (Box 1, Cassette 16-17)
- O'Connor, Patrick, May 7, 1977 (Box 1, Cassette 18)
- Peeler, William H., April 20, 1977 (Box 1, Cassette 19-20)
- Pugliano, Frank J., April 28, 1977 (Box 1, Cassette 21)
- Quinn, Thomas J., April 14, 1977 (Box 1, Cassette 22-25)
- Rath, Eugene, April 26, 1977 (Box 1, Cassette 26)
- Rice, Msgr. Charles Owen, May 10, 1977 (Box 1, Cassette 27)
- Samokar, Michael, August 17, 1976 (Box 1, Cassette 28-29)
- Smith, Alice and Dave, August 16, 1976 (Box 1, Cassette 30)
- Stasik, Margaret Darin, January 7, 1977 (Box 1, Cassette 31)
- Winn, William, August 20, 1976 (Box 1, Cassette 32-34)
- Yeager, Otto, January 6, 1977 (Box 1, Cassette 35)